Humane Borders records, 2000-2010 MS 471
University of Arizona
- Series I: Media Files, 2000-2010
  - Subseries 2: Audiovisual interviews with media and control files, 1996-2011
    - Humane Borders on the News, April 8, 2007 (Box 12, Othertype 51)
    - New Sanctuary Movement, May 9, 2007 (Box 12, Othertype 52)
    - Migrant Deaths, May 14, 2007 (Box 12, Othertype 53)
    - Hablemos de Soluciones Conferencia, February 23, 2007 (Box 13, Othertype 1)
    - American Dream: Dead or Alive Part 1 and 2, March 13, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 2)
    - Trash Cleanup, 5pm, 6pm, 10pm, May 9, 2007 (Box 13, Othertype 3)
    - Guatemalan girls split from family, August 2, 2007 (Box 13, Othertype 4)
    - Conteo Noche, June 16, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 5)
    - Board of Supervisors Meeting, August 5, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 6)
    - de Nadie, 2005 (Box 13, Othertype 7)
    - A Walk Through Cabeza, February 13, 2003 (Box 13, Othertype 8)
    - Death in the Desert, June 2004 (Box 13, Othertype 9)
    - El Drama de los immigrantes ante las nueva legislacion en Arizona, February 13, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 10)
    - Endless Exodus, undated (Box 13, Othertype 11)
    - Student film, 2002 (Box 13, Othertype 12)
    - Multiple news clips, undated (Box 13, Othertype 13)
    - Promo video, undated (Box 13, Othertype 14)
    - Surveillance/Rescue of Migrants in Desert, June 2001 (Box 13, Othertype 15)
    - Hoover speech at United Nations Advocacy Week, November 17, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 16)
    - Women Crossing Borders, June 2001 (Box 13, Othertype 17)
    - Fighting for Political Power, 1996 (Box 13, Othertype 18)
    - Beyond Borders: Faith in Action in the Arizona Desert, 2007 (Box 13, Othertype 19)
    - Shadow of Hope, 2004 (Box 13, Othertype 20)
    - A Sign of the Cross, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 21)
    - The Devil's Highway, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 22)
    - Border Safety Initative - audio only, undated (Box 13, Othertype 23)
    - Chiapas El Gran Muro Para Los Migrantes, undated (Box 13, Othertype 24)
    - Rally at Armory Park, May 1, 2006 (Box 13, Othertype 25)
    - John Carlos Frey Interviews Tim Holt, August 22, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 26)
    - Democrats in Puerto Vallarta - Edited disc., May 2, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 27)
    - Tire slasher on security camera, August 9, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 28)
    - Beyond the Border (Mas Alla de la Frontera), 2001 (Box 13, Othertype 29)
    - Humane Borders First 10 years, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 30)
    - The Situation with Tucker Carlson, January 26, 2006 (Box 13, Othertype 31)
    - The Situation Roon with Lou Dobbs, January 26, 2006 (Box 13, Othertype 32)
    - Clips of quotes by Drs. Wayne Cornelius and Raquel Rubio Goldsmith, undated (Box 13, Othertype 33)
    - Food, Inc. - Undocumented meat packing workers clip, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 34)
    - CNDH at FCC, August 4, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 35)
    - Art on Border Wall in Nogales, Sonora, March 23, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 36)
    - Aid Station at Mariposa Port of Entry, March 23, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 37)
    - Grupo Beta Offfice in Nogales, Sonora, March 23, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 38)
    - Casa San Juan Bosco Migrant Shelter, March 23, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 39)
    - DeConcini Port of Entry, undated (Box 13, Othertype 40)
    - Humane Borders Promo for General Assembly, October 17, 2003 (Box 13, Othertype 41)
    - Death in the Desert: Why Here?, January 17, 2009 (Box 13, Othertype 42)
    - John Frey's Human Rights Speech, January 17, 2009 (Box 13, Othertype 43)
    - Border Fair Panel Discussion, January 17, 2009 (Box 13, Othertype 44)
    - The Beast, 2010 (Box 13, Othertype 45)
    - Agua in the Desert, July 28, 2002 (Box 13, Othertype 46)
    - 911 Call 1415hrs Audio, July 18, 2005 (Box 13, Othertype 47)
    - Interview Mike Wison after Press Conference Audio, September 7, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 48)
    - Contra Viento y Marea, 2001 (Box 13, Othertype 49)
    - Arrancados de Raiz, 2001 (Box 13, Othertype 50)
    - The 800 Mile Wall, May 1, 2009 (Box 13, Othertype 51)
    - America 101, 2005 (Box 13, Othertype 52)
    - Poverty Trap - with Bill Clinton, September 2, 2006 (Box 13, Othertype 53)
    - Mojados Through the Night, 2004 (Box 13, Othertype 54)
    - 7 Soles, 2008 (Box 13, Othertype 55)
    - Memorial Service for Murdered Migrants, February 18, 2007 (Box 13, Othertype 56)
    - Vandalism at Water Station, 2002 (Box 13, Othertype 57)
    - Hoover Installation at FCC, March 19, 2000 (Box 13, Othertype 58)
- Series II: Correspondence, 2000-2010
  This series is in chronological order. It contains correspondence with media outlets, other religious congregations and individuals along with phone message books.
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 2000-2009
    - Signs of the Times in the Americas, Spring 2000 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - [Press Release], September 10, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - [Carol Ann Alaimo Press Release], March 15, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - [Press Conference], May 30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - National Council of Churches Statement, June 12, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - H.B. letter Re: INS Abuse Media - Non Article, July 3, 2001-July 9, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - L.D. Productions, November 1, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - AZ State Land Use Forms, November 29, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Disciples World, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Hallman, Phyllis, CWF Curriculum, circa 2002 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Peace Calendar, January 2002-February 2002 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - O'Reilly Show MSNBC, January 26, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Annerino, John, "Dead in their Tracks,", January 28, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Kimmerling, George, February 2002-May 2002 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - March 7, 2002 [First Christian Church Press Release], February 12, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - [H.B. Press Conference], March 28, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Media Interviews, May 13, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Thank Yous Received, May 31, 2002-July 16, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Rescue Flights, June 2002 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Radio Unica, June 2002-July 2002 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Rodriguez, Paul, June 1, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Van Denberg, Hart, June 4, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Vatican, Cardinal Sedano Right to Emigrate, June 5, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - INS News Release Media -Non Article, June 15, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - KXCI Radio, July 8, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - AZ Republic Waiver, July 10, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - US Commission on Civil Rights, August 23, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - National Catholic Reporter, September 24, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - French Republic Radio, October 11, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Antel, Rachel, "Death on a Friendly Border,", October 30, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Palafax, Jose, November 27, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Donahue Show MSNBC, December 9, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Full Spectrum Productions, circa 2003 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Catholic Bishops, January 2003 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Email Misc 2003, February 5, 2003-November 13, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - New Voices Grant Application, February 21, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Pinacate, February 26, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Shumow, Moses, March 12, 2003-March 13, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Protect AZ Now, July 14, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Verdoia, Ken, January 2004, January 2005 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Bush Press Conf., January 7, 2003-March 23, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Linda Valdez, January 27, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - [Julia Vasilchenko Correspondence], January 28, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Multi-Faith Border Conference, March 18, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Lazano, Carrie, April 27, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - San Damiano Fdn - Endless Exodus, June 21, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Univision, April 8, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Simpson, Richard, May 17, 2004-July 23, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - United Church of Christ, July 11, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Hwang, Irene Barcelona, August 2005 (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - KVOA, August 10, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Lesnes, Corine, October 17, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - Wunderlich, Jessica, November 18, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Station Naming, May 6, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 54)
    - Wildcat ad info, August 21, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 55)
    - Disciples Emergemcu Resolution and more, August 28, 2005-June 29, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 56)
    - Crossing Arizona, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 57)
    - Walking the Line, September 7, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 58)
    - Hunt, Davis, Washington Times, January 26, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 59)
    - Misc Correspondence, February 25, 2006-May 8, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 60)
    - Actual Reality TV, May 11, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 61)
    - McMorris, Billy, September 2, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 62)
    - Champagne, Jennifer, October 26, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 63)
    - Arizona Daily Star Letter to Bobbie Jo Buell, January 8, 2007, June 24, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 64)
    - Nexus IFC Sweden, February 15, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 65)
    - Methodist, March 9, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 66)
    - Notre Dame Book, August 17, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 67)
    - Lionsgate Films/Crash TV, August 7, 2008-September 7, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 68)
    - Thank Yous Received, February 24, 2007-August 28, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 69)
    - Kimble, Mark, Tucson Citizen, June 14, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 70)
    - Department of Interior Memo, November 17, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 71)
    - Letter to Land Manager 2009, October 21, 2009-December 8, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 72)
    - Canoa Ranch, undated (Box 14, Folder 73)
    - Documentress Films, undated (Box 14, Folder 74)
    - Eyeful Video, undated (Box 14, Folder 75)
    - Radio Unica, undated (Box 14, Folder 76)
  - Subseries 2: Phone Messages, 2001-2010
    This subseries is arranged chronologically. It contains phone message books with day to day messages from various callers to Humane Borders.
    - Phone Message Book 1, June 17, 2001-September 1, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 77)
    - Phone Message Book 2, September 4, 2001-June 11, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 78)
    - Phone Message Book 3, June 10, 2002-October 24, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 79)
    - Phone Message Book 4, October 25, 2002-May 30, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 80)
    - Phone Message Book 5, May 30, 2003-October 23, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 81)
    - Phone Message Book 6, October 27, 2003-May 19, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 82)
    - Phone Message Book 7, May 27, 2004-May 26, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Phone Message Book 8, May 27, 2005-February 28, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Phone Message Book 9, February 28, 2006-June 15, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Phone Message Book 10, June 15, 2006-January 8, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Phone Message Book 11, July 5, 2006-January 21, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Phone Message Book 12, January 12, 2007-June 29, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Phone Message Book 13, July 5, 2007-March 14, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Phone Message Book 14, August 13, 2008-March 12, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Phone Message Book 15, March 12, 2009-November 18, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Phone Message Book 16, November 16, 2009-October 11, 2010 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Blue flag from water station, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Series III: Administrative Files, 2000-2011
  This series is arranged into subseries with each subseries arranged chronologically or by format. It includes calendars, scheduling material, dissertations, legislation material, lawsuit material, event material, reports, studies and schedules. The material covers United States border policy and the humanitarian and advocacy operations of Humane Borders.
  - Subseries 1: Calendars and Meeting Notes, 2000-2009
    This subseries is arranged chronologically. It contains calendars, meeting agendas and notes.
    - Calendar, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Calendar, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Calendar, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Calendar, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Calendar, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Calendar, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - HB Monthly Mtgs, Weekly or Yearly Meeting, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Weekly Mtgs, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Weekly Mtgs, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Humane Borders Agenda Weekly meetings 1 of 2, 2005-2007 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Humane Borders Agenda Weekly meetings 2 of 2, 2005-2007 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 2: Dissertations, House and Senate Bills and Lawsuit Material, 2001-2006
    This subseries is arranged chronologically. It contains dissertations from students, text and correspondence pertaining to immigration legislation and lawsuit material over the wrongful death of migrants in the desert.
    - Lane Van Ham's Dissertation, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Cornell University Maria Lorena Cook, September 5, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Cari Eastman Dissertation, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Proposed Policy Changes, June 6, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Kolbe, Jim, July 9, 2001-January 30, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - McCain, John, June 30, 2003-March 31, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Kennedy, Feingold, Clinton Bill, May 4, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Kyl, Jon, July 20, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - HR 4437, December 6, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Ed Kahn Lawsuit, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Lawsuit, Ambrose-Marcial v. United States, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Border Patrol Shooting Lawsuit, January 2007 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Law Suit $42 Million, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Metcalf and Metcalf, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 3: Events and Remarks, 2001-2009
    This subseries is in chronological order with related events from subsequent years grouped together, such as the March for Migrants or Humane Borders Anniversary celebration. It includes documents and correspondence pertaining to events hosted or attended by Humane Borders as well as speaking notes.
    - Norteno Music Festival, August 24, 2001-August 25, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - HB: March for Migrants 01, September 2001 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - March for Migrants, September 29, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - March for Migrants flyer, September 29, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - March for Migrants, September 28, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - March for Migrants, September 26, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - March for Migrants 2005, September 22, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - 2005 March for Migrants, August 2005-September 2005 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Tucson Pastorella, December 2001 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - United Church of Christ Medfield, December 2001 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Stanford University, February 2002-March 2002 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Border Strategy Meeting El Paso 2002, February 2002-May 2002 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Exhibit, March 14, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Rolling Thunder with Jim Hightower, June 22, 2002-July 28, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - First Christian Church Ft. Worth, October 21, 2002-July 14, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Donahue Show, November 12, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - ASU Teach-In, February 2003 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - UCC 1st Congregational Hancock, New Hampshire, March 2003, January 2008 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - BANWR Centennial, March 15, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Cinco de Mayo, April 2003-May 2003 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Gatekeeper Film, May 2003-August 2006 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - U of San Diego, September 2003 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - UCC Flagstaff, September 12, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Trash Day, September 13, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Progressive Market Place, October 14, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - General Assembly, October 17, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - LIRS Exhibit Opening, October 24, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Endorsements, International Migrants Day, December 18, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Mexicali Speaking Engagement, February 2004 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Fun with Fitzsimmons, April 25, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Fitz, April 25, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Notre Dame, June 17, 2004-September 24, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Migration Theology Conference Notre Dame, September 2004 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Migration and Theology Conference, September 2004 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - UCC Youth Convention, July 2004 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - PHEWA, July 23, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - U of Minnesota, May 30, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - 5th Anniversary, June 11, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - 5th Anniversary, June 11, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Silent Auction, June 11, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Humane Borders 5th Anniversary Desert Fountain, June 11, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - 6th Anniversary, June 10, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Silent Auction, June 10, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Raffle Tickets, June 10, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - Arizona Immigration Forum, October 2005 (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Peace and Justice Day, Peace Center, October 9, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - Columbus, New Mexico, December 3, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - HB Conference 2006 (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - Mexico Trip, January 19-25, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - Progressive Club Fair U of A, January 27, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - Fresno State University, February 2006-March 2006 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - Annenberg School of Journalism, USC, March 1, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - Migrant Rallies, March 27, 2006-March 30, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Palm Sunday Witness, April 9, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Concert The Rock, May 13, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Plymouth-McAlester, June 2006 (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - Mix in 06, June 21, 2006-June 25, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - College of Public Health U of A, August 18, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - Mexico City, October 2006 (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - Higher Education and Leadership DOC, November 11, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Calexico Concerts, December 2006 (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - Mexico City Award Trip, December 2006 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Migrant Conference, December 4, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - IEC Meeting, January 2007 (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - First Anniversary Water Stations, March 7, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - Arizona Collegiate Leadership, February 2007 (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - U of GA, February 22, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 67)
    - Bay Area Trip, May 14, 2007-May 19, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 68)
    - German Parliament Reps, May 19, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 69)
    - Transatlantic Academy, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 70)
    - Davidson College, February 2008 (Box 17, Folder 71)
    - Community and Learning Service Project Week - BLM, March 4, 2009-March 28, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 72)
    - US -Mexico Border Academic Tour Wester Hemisphere Institute at U of A, April 2008 (Box 17, Folder 73)
    - Evergreen Immigrationa nd Border Dialogue Conference, May 2008 (Box 17, Folder 74)
    - Methodist Bishops Mexico Trip - 2008, June 2007-July 2008 (Box 17, Folder 75)
    - Events and Visiting Groups, June 7, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 76)
    - United Nations, November 17, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 77)
    - Border Fair, January 17, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 78)
    - HBO Documentaries, September 3, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 79)
    - Anti-militarization positions, undated (Box 17, Folder 80)
    - Check List, undated (Box 17, Folder 81)
    - Lagos De Moreno, July-August, no year (Box 17, Folder 82)
    - Silent Auction Bid Sheets, 7th Anniversary, undated (Box 17, Folder 83)
    - Mexico Trip Folder 1, January 21, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Mexico Trip Folder 2, January 21, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Sanctuary Movement 20th Anniversary, March 2002 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Events and Visiting Groups Information Pages, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Groups and Events, June 2006-August 2006 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Groups and Events, March 2007-February 2009 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Visitors and Events, June 2008-December 2008 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Conference on the Migrant, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Conference on the Migrant, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 4: Financial Reports, 2001-2009
    This subseries is arranged chronologically, it contains financial information pertaining to the operation of Humane Borders.
    - Financial Spreadsheets, 2001-2003 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Financial Reports, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Financial Reports, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Financial Reports, 2004 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Financial Reports, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Financial Reports, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Financial Reports, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Financial Reports, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Financial Reports, 2009 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 5: Operation Files and Permits, 2000-2011
    This subseries is arranged with operation files in chronological order and permits in alphabetical order. It documents the administrative operations of Humane Borders and their agreements with local governmental and private land owners.
    - Border Patrol, June 26, 2000-February 8, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Steering Committee for H.B., October 11, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Arizona State Statutes, December 12, 2001-December 13, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - [Humane Borders Discussion Paper], December 2002 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - UCC Insurance Board, February 20, 2003-July 8, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - AZ Trust Land, May 8, 2003-December 18, 2009 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Call to Elected Officials, April 4, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Old Permits and Insurance Certificates, July 28, 2003-August 15, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Winter Rescue Operation, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Robin's Lists, April 19, 2004-June 10, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Water Testing, December 2004 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Humane Borders Board of Directors Agenda, January 13, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - GIS Project, April 29, 2008-December 3, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - 2008 Cell Towers, July 19, 2008-July 21, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Ajo Map, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Cards, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Position of Militarization, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Talking Points, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Buenos Aires National Wildlife Refuge, April 17, 2000-January 14, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - BLM Phoenix 1 of 2, August 10, 2006-September 15, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - BLM Phoenix 2 of 2, July 18, 2001-August 10, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - BLM Tucson 1 of 2, May 4, 2004-January 28, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - BLM Tucson 2 of 2, December 17, 2001-February 9, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Cabeza Prieta National Wildlife, March 27, 2001-April 19, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - City of Tucson, August 2, 2001-August 17, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument, January 23, 2002-January 6, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Pima County, July 3, 2001-February 7, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Rio Rico, June 13, 2001-July 9, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Tohono O'odham, January 23, 2001-November 17, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Subseries 6: Reports and Studies, 2000-2009
    This series is in rough chronological order with similar reports or reports from the same agencies grouped together. The reports and studies document United States policy and the impact of migration on the people and environment of the Southwestern borderlands.
    - Summary of GAO Reports, 1997-2004 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - GGD-98-21 GAO SW Border Strategy, December 1997 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - GGD-99-44 GAO SW Border Strategy, May 1999 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - GGD-00-103 GAO Alien Smuggling, May 2000 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - GAO/T HEHS-00-134 H-2A Agriculture Guest Workers, June 15, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - GAO-01-842 SW Border Strategy, August 2001 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - GAO-02-861T Interior Enforcement Strategy, June 19, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 36)